<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>webcam on Greg. I/O</title>
    <link>https://gautric.github.io/tags/webcam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in webcam on Greg. I/O</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gautric.github.io/tags/webcam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Activer/Désactiver sa camera PoE via son routeur Cisco</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2024/01/28/activer-desactiver-sa-camera-poe-via-son-routeur-cisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2024/01/28/activer-desactiver-sa-camera-poe-via-son-routeur-cisco/</guid>
      <description>Dans ce post, nous allons rapidement voir comment activer ou désactiver une caméra via un routeur Cisco. Chez moi, j&amp;rsquo;ai mis en place une installation permettant la télésurveillance en mode DIY. J&amp;rsquo;utilise une caméra en mode PoE avec un routeur Small Business de la marque Cisco. Plus précisément, il s&amp;rsquo;agit du Cisco Commutateur Intelligent SG250-10P, qui offre la fonctionnalité PoE.
Activer/Désactiver sa camera PoE depuis son routeur Cisco
Pré-requis Avant de commencer il faut pouvoir se connecter en SSH sur le routeur.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RHIoT Webcam and websocket components on MacbookPro in Groovy</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/10/23/rhiot-camel-webcam-websocket-macbookpro.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/10/23/rhiot-camel-webcam-websocket-macbookpro.html</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, we&amp;rsquo;ve played with our MacBook Pro&amp;rsquo;s webcam. Today, we gonna see how to send images through a websocket directly in this page !!! or via a JavaFx program. We gonna re-use the previous post and integrate camel Websocket component. Let&amp;rsquo;s play with Groovy language &amp;hellip;
Webcam image to Websocket w/ Rhiot &amp;amp; Camel projects on MacbookPro
Let&amp;rsquo;s start to broadcast yourself.
Requisites Have a mac tested MacBook Pro Retina, 13-inch, Mid 2014 Groovy Mac port installed Groovy Version: 2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RHIoT 0.1.2 Webcam component on MacOS X in Groovy</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/10/22/rhiot-0.1.2-camel-webcam-macos-x.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/10/22/rhiot-0.1.2-camel-webcam-macos-x.html</guid>
      <description>My tech leader on RHIoT project (ex-camellabs) Henryk had just release the last version of RHIoT project : 0.1.2. Lot of new stuffs are included in this new release, more details available here. I found in list a cool stuff to test. We gonna check if our new commiter @levackt from ZA worked well ;-)
Webcam camel component on Mac OSX with Groovy language
Let&amp;rsquo;s start to broadcast yourself.
Requisites Have a mac tested MacBook Pro Retina, 13-inch, Mid 2014 Groovy Mac port installed Groovy Version: 2.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
