<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jboss on Greg. I/O</title>
    <link>https://gautric.github.io/tags/jboss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jboss on Greg. I/O</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 14:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gautric.github.io/tags/jboss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JBoss EAP 7 connected to WebsphereMQ running on Docker</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/08/03/jboss-eap-7-connected-to-webspheremq-running-on-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/08/03/jboss-eap-7-connected-to-webspheremq-running-on-docker/</guid>
      <description>Last year for a previous customer I wrote an article/post about WebsphereMQ Best Practice with JBoss EAP 6. Today we will make almost the same stuff but with JBoss EAP 7, WebsphereMQ Sample IVT application and running on Docker. I assume you know basic command about Docker.
Howto run JBoss EAP 7 connected to WebsphereMQ both running on Docker
Prerequisites For this lab, you need the following software :
package of JBoss EAP 7 http://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JConsole &amp; Java Mission Control with JBoss EAP 7</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/07/19/jconsole-java-mission-control-with-jboss-eap-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/07/19/jconsole-java-mission-control-with-jboss-eap-7/</guid>
      <description>During Red Hat summit, Red Hat releases the new version of its JBoss Application Server. JBoss App Server provides a new JMX Remote Management protocol to connect with. A common JMX tool is JConsole and we will see how to use it with remote mode. We also configure an other tool called Java Mission Control for a cooler JMX monitoring stuff. Sorry my platform is a MacOS X, but I am sure your skill is enough to adapt into your environment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lancement de JBoss EAP 7</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/06/27/lancement-de-jboss-eap-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/06/27/lancement-de-jboss-eap-7/</guid>
      <description>Cela fait exactement 5 ans que je travaille pour Red Hat et pour mon cadeau d&amp;rsquo;anniversaire Red Hat vient de sortir sa nouvelle version de son serveur d&amp;rsquo;application phare à savoir JBoss EAP 7. Cette nouvelle version de JBoss EAP 7 presente certaine evolutions interessantes par rapport à la version 6, tout en gradant la philosophie et l&amp;rsquo;architecture générale du serveur d&amp;rsquo;application. Nous allons voir dans ce post les principaux elements qui me semblent le plus interessant à retenir de cette nouvelle version.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices Websphere MQ/JBoss EAP 6 English Version</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/03/26/best-practices-websphere-mq/jboss-eap-6-english-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/03/26/best-practices-websphere-mq/jboss-eap-6-english-version/</guid>
      <description>JBoss EAP application server is Java EE 6 certified, it implements via IronJacamar framework, the Java EE Connector Architecture (JCA) standard. This standard provides connection ability for Java EE applications to interact with external data system like JMS broker, file system or mainframe. The JCA standard is similar to the JDBC standard. The latter interacts only with relational databases but JCA can interact with more data system providers and it can integrate different kinds of Enterprise Information System (EIS).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices Websphere MQ/JBoss EAP 6</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/03/25/best-practices-websphere-mq/jboss-eap-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/03/25/best-practices-websphere-mq/jboss-eap-6/</guid>
      <description>Le serveur d&amp;rsquo;application JBoss EAP est certifié JAVA EE 6, il implémente donc via le framework IronJacamar le standard JAVA EE Connector Architecture (JCA). Ce standard permet de connecter les applications Java EE à des ressources externes comme par exemple un broker JMS, un système de fichier ou un mainframe. Il est possible de faire l&amp;rsquo;analogie du standard JCA avec le standard JDBC, JDBC se limitant uniquement aux bases de données de type relationnel, JCA se veut beaucoup plus large, il permet d&amp;rsquo;intégrer tout type de systèmes d’informations d’entreprise (EIS)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yubico OTP et JBoss EAP 6 ou Wildfly 8</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/03/19/yubico-otp-et-jboss-eap-6-ou-wildfly-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/03/19/yubico-otp-et-jboss-eap-6-ou-wildfly-8/</guid>
      <description>Yubikey est une clef de crypto qui permet d&amp;rsquo;avoir une authentification forte lors d&amp;rsquo;un processus de connexion à un site web (par ex : banque, web mail, etc&amp;hellip;.). Plusieurs sites web commencent à inclure cette fonctionnalité lors du processus d&amp;rsquo;authentification à leur service. L&amp;rsquo;utilisateur utilise un token généré par sa clef comme mot de passe. Ce mot de passe est aléatoire, est vérifié par le système et change à chaque utilisation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
