<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Camel on Greg. I/O</title>
    <link>https://gautric.github.io/tags/camel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Camel on Greg. I/O</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.154.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://gautric.github.io/tags/camel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Camel XML XPath XSLT Aggregator</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/12/03/camel-xml-xpath-xslt-aggregator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/12/03/camel-xml-xpath-xslt-aggregator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month I went to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greece&#34;&gt;Greece&lt;/a&gt; for a customer of mine. I worked at Athens on &lt;a href=&#34;http://camel.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Camel&lt;/a&gt; integration with Mainframe legacy systems. The customer wanted to use XML message format throughout the entire Camel route process. Their primary goal was to reuse some Camel routes as new service components, allowing for greater flexibility and modularity in their integration architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the Camel framework meets all of these requirements out of the box. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore a simple example demonstrating how to implement this approach effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Camel is going into Eclipse Kura</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/03/18/camel-is-going-into-eclipse-kura/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2016/03/18/camel-is-going-into-eclipse-kura/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I am going to talk about some exciting news in the IoT development world. This is a technical post, but without any code samples or hardware setup instructions (thankfully). The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eclipse.org/kura/&#34;&gt;Eclipse Kura Project&lt;/a&gt; has accepted a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/eclipse/kura/pull/72&#34;&gt;GitHub Pull Request&lt;/a&gt; that introduces a powerful new component to the &lt;code&gt;develop&lt;/code&gt; branch. This new component is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://camel.apache.org&#34;&gt;Camel Framework&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://about.me/hekonsek&#34;&gt;Henryk Konsek&lt;/a&gt;, a talented colleague of mine, is the principal developer behind this integration. The relationship between Camel and Kura actually began earlier with the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://camel.apache.org/kura.html&#34;&gt;Camel Kura component&lt;/a&gt;, which has been available since Camel version 2.15, also developed by Henryk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RHIoT RaspberryPi Sense-Hat display</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/11/24/rhiot-raspberrypi-sense-hat-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/11/24/rhiot-raspberrypi-sense-hat-display/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I bought the new official &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/products/sense-hat/&#34;&gt;Sense-HAT&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org&#34;&gt;RaspberryPi foundation&lt;/a&gt;. This &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.raspberrypi.org/blog/introducing-raspberry-pi-hats/&#34;&gt;HAT&lt;/a&gt; (Hardware Attached on Top) add-on for the RaspberryPi device includes lots of cool features and sensors. The Sense-HAT comes with an 8x8 RGB565 pixel display, a Joystick, a Gyroscope, Accelerometer, Magnetometer, Temperature, Barometric pressure and Humidity sensors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All sensors are i2c compliant, making them easily accessible with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rhiot/rhiot/tree/master/docs#i2c-driver&#34;&gt;rhiot camel-pi4j&lt;/a&gt; component. This makes it very straightforward to retrieve data from all sensors and transmit them to external systems. The Rhiot team has also developed the first implementation of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rhiot/rhiot/tree/master/components/camel-framebuffer&#34;&gt;rhiot camel-framebuffer component&lt;/a&gt;, which now enables pushing images directly to the 8x8 pixel screen. Note that the matrix consists of 8x8 RGB565 LEDs (2 bytes per pixel), providing a colorful display despite its small size.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RHIoT Webcam and websocket components on MacbookPro in Groovy</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/10/23/rhiot-webcam-and-websocket-components-on-macbookpro-in-groovy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/10/23/rhiot-webcam-and-websocket-components-on-macbookpro-in-groovy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, we&amp;rsquo;ve played with our MacBook Pro&amp;rsquo;s webcam. Today, we gonna see how to send images through a websocket
directly in this page !!! or via a JavaFx program. We gonna re-use the previous post and integrate camel Websocket component. Let&amp;rsquo;s play with Groovy language to create a real-time webcam streaming solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Webcam image to Websocket w/ Rhiot &amp;amp; Camel projects on MacbookPro&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start to broadcast yourself. This tutorial will guide you through setting up a webcam stream that can be viewed through a web browser or a JavaFX application.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RHIoT 0.1.2 Webcam component on MacOS X in Groovy</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/10/22/rhiot-0.1.2-webcam-component-on-macos-x-in-groovy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/10/22/rhiot-0.1.2-webcam-component-on-macos-x-in-groovy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My tech leader on &lt;a href=&#34;http://rhiot.io&#34;&gt;RHIoT project&lt;/a&gt; (ex-camellabs) &lt;a href=&#34;http://henryk-konsek.blogspot.fr/2015/10/rhiot-012-is-out.html&#34;&gt;Henryk&lt;/a&gt; had just release the last version of RHIoT project : 0.1.2.
Lot of new stuffs are included in this new release, more details available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rhiot/rhiot/blob/master/docs/release-notes.md#012--2015-10-22&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
I found in list a cool stuff to test. We gonna check if our new commiter &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/levackt&#34;&gt;@levackt&lt;/a&gt; from ZA worked well ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Webcam camel component on Mac OSX with Groovy language&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start to broadcast yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requisites&#34;&gt;Requisites&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a mac&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tested MacBook Pro Retina, 13-inch, Mid 2014&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groovy Mac port installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Groovy Version: 2.4.4 JVM: 1.8.0_45 Vendor: Oracle Corporation OS: Mac OS X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;program&#34;&gt;Program&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gonna use Groovy language for this simple example. Groovy provides a concise and expressive syntax that makes it perfect for quickly testing new components like this webcam integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Camel IoT Labs i2c gpio mqtt lcd</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/05/20/camel-iot-labs-i2c-gpio-mqtt-lcd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/05/20/camel-iot-labs-i2c-gpio-mqtt-lcd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One month ago, Henryk, Claus and I started the Camel Labs project. This project provides exciting new components for the IoT community based on Apache Camel technology. These components connect electronic devices (I2C, SPI, GPIO, Tinkerforge) and cloud services (PubNub, Cloudlet, MQTT) together. In this lab, we will demonstrate how to build an end-to-end IoT integration with I2C devices, an MQTT broker, and an I2C LCD display using just a few lines of code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Les premiers jours du projet Camel IoT Labs</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/les-premiers-jours-du-projet-camel-iot-labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/04/25/les-premiers-jours-du-projet-camel-iot-labs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui, l&amp;rsquo;Internet des Objets (IoT) prend une place de plus en plus importante dans l&amp;rsquo;industrie informatique et au-delà. Des montres connectées &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.withings.com/fr/withings-activite.html&#34;&gt;Withings&lt;/a&gt;, aux &lt;a href=&#34;http://raspberrypi.org&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; vendus à plus de 5 millions d&amp;rsquo;unités, en passant par les cartes &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arduino.cc/&#34;&gt;Arduino&lt;/a&gt; à bas coût et autres modules &lt;a href=&#34;https://tessel.io/&#34;&gt;Tessel&lt;/a&gt;, la baisse du coût de production des objets électroniques a permis une large diffusion de ces nouvelles technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://gautric.github.io/img/camel-labs.png&#34; style=&#34;max-width:120%;&#34; align=&#34;left&#34; height=&#34;110&#34; hspace=&#34;30&#34;/&gt; En 2012, les premiers Raspberry Pi sont lancés sur le marché, et j&amp;rsquo;en ai immédiatement acquis un. Depuis, j&amp;rsquo;ai collectionné presque tous les modèles : B rev1, B rev2, B+ et B2 ;-). J&amp;rsquo;ai également repris mon fer à souder, comme à l&amp;rsquo;époque du lycée. Mais contrairement à cette époque où l&amp;rsquo;on disposait de peu de ressources internet, peu de standards et peu de matériel, aujourd&amp;rsquo;hui nous avons presque tout à notre disposition. Il ne reste plus qu&amp;rsquo;à assembler des briques physiques avec des briques logicielles plus ou moins évoluées.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel RaspberryPi PoC</title>
      <link>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/04/03/apache-camel-raspberrypi-poc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 13:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gautric.github.io/blog/2015/04/03/apache-camel-raspberrypi-poc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;integrating-apache-camel-with-raspberry-pi-for-iot-applications&#34;&gt;Integrating Apache Camel with Raspberry Pi for IoT Applications&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things (IoT) revolution is transforming how we interact with the physical world through technology. At the heart of many IoT projects are two key components: affordable, capable hardware and flexible integration software. This article explores how to combine the popular Raspberry Pi single-board computer with Apache Camel, a powerful enterprise integration framework, to create IoT solutions that bridge the physical and digital worlds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
